<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Website</title>
    <link>https://skubidu.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 16:43:40 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://skubidu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study - Bike Sharing Dataset</title>
      <link>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/art006/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 16:43:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/art006/</guid>
      <description>Case Study Overview   The data can be accessed using following link: Dataset Source
  Objective
 This dataset contain the hourly and daily count of rental bikes between years 2011 and 2012 in capital bikeshare syste with the corresponding weather and seasonal information.    The regression goal is to predict beke count given various attributs.
  Download the Data and save it in the Folder Desktop/Python/Data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advantages and Limitation of Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/art005/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 16:28:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/art005/</guid>
      <description>Advantages and Disadvantages - Linear Regression Anvantages  Simple and efficient. Easily interpretable. Low variance ML model. Easy to implement as compared other complex ML approaches. If the relationshiop between the independet and dependet variable have a linear relationship, this algorithm is the best to use because it&#39;s the least complex as compared to other ML methods.  Disadvantages  It requires tranformation of non-linear features. Non-linear interactions between predictors are not captured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Various Concepts Around Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/art004/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 14:43:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/art004/</guid>
      <description>Various Concepts Around Linear Regression Interpreting Regression Output Slope $(\beta_i)$ / Intercept-$(\beta_0)$ Estimated chage in the average value of Y resulting from 1-unit change in the input feature $X_i.$ Whereas intercept term measured the average Value of Y When X = 0.
$R^2$ R-square explains what proprtion of the total variation is explained by the regression equation, which obviously implies that higher R-square values indicates better model.
Adjusted $R^2$ Since R square will continue increasing with each additional regressor (x variable) coming in, it tends to overfit the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation and Prediction Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/art003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 10:24:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/art003/</guid>
      <description>Linear Regression - Illustrative Example   Linear Regression
  Inference of Parameters - Significance of Estimate  The final equation for LR (vectorised format):
$$ \hat{Y} = h_{\Theta}(X) = \Theta.X = [\Theta_0 + \Theta_1X_1 + \Theta_2X_2 + \ldots + \Theta_nX_n] $$ MSE (Mean Square Function) - cost function of LR model:
$$ MSE(X, h_\Theta) = \frac{1}{n} \sum_{i=1}^{n}(Theta^{T}\cdot X_{(i)}-y_{(i)})^2 $$ The estimated coefficients:
$$ [(X^T\cdot X) - \ ^1X^{T}\cdot Y] $$  Steps to Build a Linear Regression Model  Data cleaning - missing calues and outlier treatment Check for multi-collinearity Feature selection Build the Model on Train Data Performance evalution on the test data  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Models</title>
      <link>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/art002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 09:37:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/art002/</guid>
      <description>Linear Regression Content  Introduction - Linear Regression Estimation and prediction - Linear Regression Varios concepts anround Linear Regression Advantages and limitation of Linear Regression Case study - bike sharing dataset  Intruction to Linear Regression Linear Regression - An Overview Supervised algorithm for Regression. A form of a parametric model.
LR refers to a model which can show relationship between two variables.
Linear relationsship between tow or more variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learing Algorithms in 7 Days</title>
      <link>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/art001/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 09:23:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/art001/</guid>
      <description>By Shovon Sengupta
7 Key Algorithms in just 7 Days Instructor Shovon Sengupta
  Over 10 years of experience as Data Science Professional with experiences in Advanced Machine Learning an Predictive Analytics
  Currently working in Capacity as a Senior Lead Data Scientist in one of the USA based financial giant
  Specializie in Deep Learnin, Reinforcement Learning
  Contact: https://www.linkedin.com/in/shovon-sengupta-272aa917/
  Course Overview Section 1 Linear Models</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://skubidu.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 18:49:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skubidu.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Some facts about me but not to much.
Coming soon&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Print</title>
      <link>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/python-print/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 18:42:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skubidu.github.io/blog/python-print/</guid>
      <description>Python Print Print is very useful!
print(&amp;#34;Lenin&amp;#34;) My next article Here I Post my next article which hopefully will be updated!
It was updated, I am so excited!
New Title </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>